William Morris



contact@morrisgwilliam.com



909-548-1515



linkedin.com/in/william-morris-77323913b



https://morrisgwilliam.com

Summary

Experienced Developer with a demonstrated history of working with HTML, JavaScript, C#, AWS and more. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor of Science - BS focused in Biotechnology with a minor in Chemistry from California State Polytechnic University-Pomona.

Experience



Full Stack Engineer

Affinity, Inc.

Feb 2021 - Present (11 months +)

Automated Deployment process using CI/CD pipelines

Designed AWS infrastructure for serverless applications using the following services/technologies: DynamoDB, Cloudfront, ACM, S3 API Gateway, Lambda, Secrets Manager, Route53, Sendgrid, ReactJS, AWS CDK, NodeJS

Designed wireframes/workflows using Figma

Participated in meetings with clients for demos and technical presentations

Full Stack Web Developer & AWS Cloud Architect

The Famous Group

Mar 2020 - Present (1 year 10 months +)

Developed a containerized web application functioning as a CMS for digital media to be scheduled and displayed on displays throughout the AT&T stadium in Dallas, Texas.

Created a Web API application for RESTful endpoints consumed by third party vendors using dotnet core, Entity Framework, and docker containers.

Provided security by leveraging encryption at rest for data stored in a SQL Server instance.

Created a React based UI for users to utilize features with drag and drop and async http requests.

Created AWS Cloud Architectures for various projects requiring cloud hosting and scaling features.

Developed an email registration system used by the WWE for virtual streaming of events such as SmackDown, RAW and pay-per-view events.

Designed lambda functions in NodeJS to integrate with DynamoDB and Simple Email Service.

Designed cloudformation templates to manage the API GateWay as a trigger for lambda functions.

Managed releases and deployments of feature releases using GitHub and GitFlow.

Created React based UI for user registration hosted by S3 and CloudFront.



Full Stack Developer

Applied Business Software Inc., Aug 2019 - Mar 2020 (8 months)

Developed a SASS web application version of the flagship products The Loan Office to have greater consumer reach. Responsibilities included creating mobile responsive pages displaying dynamic content using Web Forms and existing C# class libraries. The data layer leveraged ADO and T-SQL for data access. The UI leveraged AJAX, jQuery and bootstrap for an immersive UI experience.



Developer

Kukdong Apparel (America), Inc.

Apr 2019 - Jul 2019 (4 months)

Developing Enterprise Management Systems (EMS) using ASP.NET Web API, React and MSSQL. Duties include database schema design, building RESTful APIs and resourceful a user interface. Some technologies used include, but are not limited to, Entity Framework, Material-UI and web socket push notifications.



🦈 Full Stack Developer

Good Dog App

Dec 2018 - Mar 2019 (4 months)

Developed a minimal viable product (MVP) that tracks walking habits for Dog Lovers. Good Dog was implemented as a single-page ReactJS web application backed by Microsoft SQL Server exposed via RESTful Web API. The web client employs responsive web design practices for desktop, tablet and mobile devices.



Freelance Web Developer

Various small businesses

Jan 2018 - Nov 2018 (11 months)

Developed static websites to provide an online presence using Javascript, jQuery, HTML, and CSS. Integrated automated an email service for users to make appointments with the business.

Developed UI for users to navigate business hours and product information using responsive web design patterns.



Fairfay, Lab Technician

Fairfax Cryobank

Jul 2017 - Jan 2018 (7 months)

Managed laboratory activity, equipment and maintained a cryobank of specimens.

Performed evaluation of specimens to determine if they are acceptable to World Health Organization

Prepared specimens for cryopreservation by implementing gradient filtration and dehydration steps.



Research Fellowship

California Institute for Regenerative Medicine

Mar 2016 - Sep 2016 (7 months)

A program sponsored by the California Institute of Regenerative Medicine providing 6 month fellowships at academic laboratories in the field of stem cell research. Received training from the USC Stem Cell Core in stem cell culture techniques. I carried out my fellowship at Cal Tech investigating the role of mitochondrial fusion and spermatogenesis in conditional knockout mouse models.

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Cal Poly Pomona Foundation, Inc.

Dec 2014 - Mar 2016 (1 year 4 months)

As an undergraduate researcher I determined the efficacy of an experimental liposomal protein vaccine on mouse models. My research consisted of administering different vaccine formulations, challenging the mice with the pathogen, and performing immunological assays on tissue and blood samples.

Education



California State Polytechnic University-Pomona

Bachelor of Science - BS, Biotechnology with a minor in Chemistry 2011 - 2017

Licenses & Certifications



AWS Certified Developer - Assoicate - Amazon Web Services (AWS)



AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate - Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Issued Jul 2020 - Expires Jul 2023 9WEF8R7CHJBEQS9L

Skills

React.js • Microsoft SQL Server • .NET • C# • jQuery • HTML • Javascript • ADO.NET • SASS • Redux

Honors & Awards



AddiHacks Second Place Winner - AddiHacks

Feb 2019

Provided solutions to improve personal and business commutes by leveraging the internet of things, smart sensors, autonomous vehicles, and to innovate transportation platforms such as Uber or Lyft to decrease congestion and to reduce pollution. This ultimately improved the quality of life for people living in cities.